LIAM TIMMS

Digital marketing & design

BIO

A digital design specialist and successful marketing executive renowned for being a problem-solver. Able to manage multiple websites & design projects, create engaging marketing collateral and work with agencies to the shortest of deadlines.

Always working with a cool head and calm demeanour. A natural at thinking on my feet.

AIM

For the past 6 years, I've worked in both B2B and B2C positions with a focus on digital and design. Now, I would like to take these honed skills and continue my career in digital marketing and development.

EDUCATION

University of Gloucestershire B/A Honours Degree in Advertising - 2:2

Oxford & Cherwell Valley College BTEC Nation Diploma in ICT – DMM

Wheatley Park Secondary School GVNQ in IT – Distinction 6 GCSEs – grades B – C

CONTACT

E: Liamotimms@hotmail.co.uk
T: 07729415708
www.linkedin.com/in/liam-timms-UK
https://liam-timms.github.io/portfolio/

EXPERIENCE

No5 Barristers' Chambers July 2020 – current *Digital Marketing Coordinator (Legal Services – B2C/B2B)*

- Managing and creation of designs for event stands, advertisements, flyers and promotional materials.
- Organising visual and UI/UX improvements to company websites and managing developments.
- Innovating company email templates and managing A/B testing to develop maximum customer interaction.
- Creating digital assets including branded website imagery, video content, photography and web wireframes.
- Regular reporting on success of campaigns to senior staff and board members to define future implementation.
- Daily management of social media channels including advertising (Facebook Campaigns and LinkedIn inMail).
- Improving site performance with SEO and technical SEO.
- Developing brand guidelines across various company brands and advising on brand usage.
- Implementing website amends from all barristers (over 250 in total) and managing document release schedules.

AFH Wealth Management October 2018 – July 2020 *Digital Marketing Executive (Financial Services - B2C)*

- Managing and outlining improvement schedules for the AFH customer-facing websites and customer portals.
- Developing two-week sprints of development and changes for the company website based on stakeholder input.
- Managing in-house development team and working with external creative and digital agencies.
- Creating page wireframes, processing content changes and implementing designs in SiteCore, umbraco and Wordpress CMS.
- Setting up A/B testing within the SiteCore CMS to determine the success of new site content.
- QA for each sprint and assisting with front-end development and component design.
- Ensuring brand is consistent across all digital media.
- Advising project managers from a digital perspective.
- Using with Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics to keep track of specific goals/KPIs and improve technical SEO.
- Improve site content SEO using SEMRush and Ispionage.
- Training staff on HTML and CMS usage. Includes Wordpress, Umbraco and SiteCore.
- Photo and image manipulation for websites and social media.

Continued below

INTERESTS

Gaming, Film, Lindy Hop (dancing), Design, Weightlifting, Mud runs, Languages (currently learning Romanian)

CURRENTLY STUDYING

- Front end development
- PHP for beginners
- UX and UI Web design
- · Agile project management

EXPERIENCE (continued)

West Midlands Growth Company November 2016 – October 2018 *Marketing Executive (Inward investment – B2B)*

- Managing digital marketing campaigns across Business
- Birmingham's five main sectors engineering, life sciences, tech & digital, food and BPFS
- Creating and designing a range of printed and digital media for the all sectors within the company including film, infographics and animations.
- Creating and designing e-newsletter campaigns for Business Birmingham, corporate partners and HS2.
- Interacting and managing stakeholders and multiple marketing agencies daily
- Daily running of social media and multiple websites under the Business Birmingham brand
- Writing briefs and marking tenders for the marketing framework for Business Birmingham and Marketing Birmingham campaigns.

West Midlands Growth Company August 2015 – November 2018 *Project Executive (Relocation services – B2C)*

West Midlands Growth Company May 2015 – August 2015 *Marketing Assistant (Events & web – B2C)*

Cogent Elliott June 2014 – February 2015

Marketing Services Executive(Land Rover international – B2C)

For further work experience, 2006 – '16 please visit my LinkedIn page

KEY SKILLS

- Adobe Creative Cloud including Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and After Effects
- Able to manage multiple projects and take on ad-hoc tasks whilst managing stakeholder expectations.
- HTML fluent with strong understanding of CSS. Experience with Bootstrap.
- Experience in training junior staff members on systems.
- Able to use multiple CMS systems including Tridion, Umbraco, Wordpress and SiteCore.
- Experience with Communigator, DevOps, Trello, Survey Monkey and MailChimp.
- Productive and effective communication skills with both colleagues and stakeholders on a variety of levels.